<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Lyuwen Fu</title><link>https://lyuwenfu.me/</link><description>Recent content on Lyuwen Fu</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 00:53:33 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lyuwenfu.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Building CI/CD workflow for my CV</title><link>https://lyuwenfu.me/posts/ci-workflow-for-cv/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 00:53:33 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://lyuwenfu.me/posts/ci-workflow-for-cv/</guid><description>In this project, I&amp;rsquo;ve built an CI/CD workflow with GitHub Actions to automatically build and deploy my CV to GitHub Pages whenever it&amp;rsquo;s updated.
Docker Image of TeXLive First of all, my CV is written in LaTeX the fundation of the workflow is building LaTeX files. Thus an installation of TeXLive is needed as it&amp;rsquo;s the standard TeX distribution. However, a TeXLive distribution is massive and takes at least 10s of minutes to install, and there is also the issue of the outdated TeX Live distribution that is available with Ubuntu&amp;rsquo;s APT package manager.</description></item><item><title>Principia Materia</title><link>https://lyuwenfu.me/posts/principia-materia/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lyuwenfu.me/posts/principia-materia/</guid><description>Principia Materia (PM) is a materials computation and simulation package started with my advisor Prof. Chris Marianetti during my doctoral research.
With a codebase of around 20 thousand lines, the object oriented software package is optimized with over 10$\times$ improvements on time complexity comparing to the existing software while computing at the same level of precision.
Although our work emphasizes on the computation of phonons and phonon interactions as well as the prediction of materials thermodynamic and transport properties, the modular design of the package allows its individual parts to be used in a variety materials studies, including the electronic properties of materials, symmetry analysis of other materials properties, etc.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://lyuwenfu.me/about/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 18:26:44 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://lyuwenfu.me/about/</guid><description>About me I just earned my Ph.D. degree working with my advisor Prof. Chris Marianetti on Thermodynamics of Interacting Phonons at Columbia University. We are currently developing a highly optimized software that executes the methodologies described in the paper we published. It will be released soon. Stay tuned.
My CV can be found here.
Education Columbia University, New York, New York Jan 2017 - Oct 2021 Ph.</description></item></channel></rss>